Kaiju No. 8...
怪獸8號…
I can't believe there was a Kaiju inside the Defense Force.
沒想到怪獸竟然混入了防衛隊
And a Daikaiju class, too.
而且還是大怪獸等級
We need to deal with this immediately.
這件事得盡快處理
Do we tell the media?
要通知媒體嗎？
We ought to keep this under wraps, as we did with Kaiju No. 9.
應該要像9號那次一樣，不對外透露
I hear rumors that one country is experimenting
據悉已有某個國家正在進行實驗
with Kaiju-to-human tissue transplants.
將怪獸組織移植至人體
They'd try something if they knew.
他們可不會悶不吭聲
The obvious move is to dispose of it in secret and convert it into weaponry.
應該立即暗中處決牠，再轉作兵器使用
Shouldn't we consider using it as a living weapon first?
在那之前，是否應該先考慮 把牠當成活體兵器運用？
This discussion is getting us nowhere.
紙上談兵也沒用
We bring it in first, then decide.
等拘留之後再決定處置方式吧
EPISODE 11: KAIJU NO. 8 CAPTURED
（第11集：被捕的怪獸8號）
Kaiju No. 8's vitals are stable.
怪獸8號的生命徵象穩定
It shows no signs of transforming.
也沒有變身的跡象
Is that really...?
他真的是…
It's been a full day, huh?
已經過整整一天了吧
What happens to me now?
接下來，我會怎麼樣？
When a Kaiju's powerful enough to get a number,
擁有編號的怪獸
I've heard they use its body as parts for a special weapon after they defeat it.
被打倒之後，聽說會被用來 做成特殊兵器的零件
It's possible that'll happen to you.
最壞的情況，你就會變成這樣
Just when I'd taken a step closer to being by her side...
我明明好不容易才離她更近一步了
I'm sure Mina's mad.
米娜應該很生氣吧
It's time.
時間到了
We're transporting you to HQ's facilities.
現在將你移交至總部設施
Mina...
米娜
Vice-Captain! I'm sorry! I...
副隊長，對不起，我…
Don't say a word.
別說話
Stand up.
站起來
Figures.
這樣也很合理
I have been keeping one hell of a secret from them.
畢竟我隱瞞了天大的祕密
The security detail is ready to accompany him.
同行的警備部隊已準備就緒
Oh no... I can't even look him in the eyes.
糟糕，我無法直視他的臉
He's done so much to look out for me.
他一直都很關心我
He's probably so mad.
他應該無法原諒我吧
I'm sorry.
對不起
This time, it's really ove——
這次真的結束…
Senpai!
前輩
I have faith that you'll come back, okay?
我相信你會回來的
Ichikawa.
市川
Ichikawa's going to be doing 50 push-ups for talking out of turn.
市川這傢伙擅自發言 要罰他50下伏地挺身
Mina?
米娜
There are no cameras in here.
這裡沒有監視器
When you dashed in to save us all without a moment's hesitation,
你毫不猶豫衝去拯救大家的時候
I was shocked to see you as a Kaiju.
看到你變成怪獸的模樣，讓我很震驚
But I also told myself...
同時卻也覺得…
that's just like you.
那個舉動很符合你的作風
I'm putting together testimony and footage that will help you.
我們正在搜集對你有利的證詞和影像
If we can prove you're human, we might be able to save you.
如果可以證明你是人類 也許就能讓你免於遭受處分
We're also going to report on everything you've done as an officer.
我們也打算一起呈報你身為隊員的貢獻
Nobody in the Third Division
第3部隊裡沒有任何人
thinks of you as an enemy.
把你視為敵人
It's time.
時間到了
Sit down.
坐下
Kafka Hibino.
日比野卡夫卡
In accordance with Article 13 of the Defense Force Code,
現在依防衛隊規則第13條
you are to be transferred to the Ariake Maritime Base.
將你移交至有明臨海基地
-To ensure the safety of the citizenry—— -Mina.
-為確保沿途市民安危… -米娜
Can I still...
我還能夠…
try to stand by your side?
追求與你並肩的這個目標嗎？
Yeah.
嗯
I'll always be waiting.
我會一直等你
Idiot.
蠢蛋
Third Defense Force, salute!
第3部隊，敬禮！
Vice-Captain Hoshina, what do you think you're doing?
保科副隊長，你這是在做什麼？
I'm saluting my superior officer, Captain Ashiro.
這是在向長官亞白隊長致敬
Of course you are.
也對
We can't have anyone saluting to a Kaiju.
向怪獸敬禮，成何體統
Of course.
是的
DEFENSE FORCE ARIAKE MARITIME BASE
（防衛隊有明臨海基地）
Bulkheads 23 to 31 are completely sealed.
第23至第31分隔牆已正常鎖定
Kaiju No. 8 is now contained.
怪獸8號，拘禁完畢
SEVERAL DAYS LATER
（數天後）
I still can't believe it, you know.
我到現在還是不敢相信
Who woulda thought that the old man was Kaiju No. 8?
沒想到大叔竟然是怪獸8號
I mean, the guy's got one heck of a spare tire.
畢竟他可是凸肚大叔耶
Right, Reno?
對吧，雷諾？
Hibino-san saved me from the Kaiju.
日比野從怪獸手中救出了我
He found the Kaiju's weak points.
他還會找出怪獸的弱點
And he was always so much fun to be around in training.
訓練的時候，他也總是很開朗
I mean, he saved my life too.
我也是多虧了大叔才得救
We don't get to decide.
能作出決定的不是我們
The Neutralization Bureau does.
而是討伐廳
That's a former SDF officer.
不愧是前任自衛隊軍官
Always following orders.
上情下達對你來說是理所當然呢
You're right, though.
但你說得沒錯
The fact that a human turned into a Kaiju is a big deal.
人類變成怪獸這件事非同小可
If it gets out, we're looking at a worldwide panic.
這個事實一旦公布，全世界都會陷入恐慌
The whole world's gonna have to live every day wondering
一想到身邊的人搞不好其實是怪獸
if the person standing next to them is actually a Kaiju.
大家從此都會活得提心吊膽
No...
怎麼會…
This is too much for us to get involved in.
這已經不是我們能插手的問題了
Senpai...
前輩…
Enter.
進來吧
Excuse me.
打擾了
You called?
您找我什麼事？
Put all this together for me.
幫我把這些彙整一下
On the double, please.
有點緊急
Okay.
好的
This is all...
這是…
Can you do it?
可以拜託你嗎？
Yes, of course.
是，當然可以
Vice-Captain.
副隊長
We've cleared out all the destroyed vehicles.
廢棄車輛已撤除完畢
Oh, thanks.
好，辛苦了
What will happen to Hibino, you think?
日比野的下場會如何？
I'm going to need him back here.
我需要他回來
When he was fighting with me, he wasn't using his full strength.
那傢伙跟我對戰時，他手下留情了
Who's he think he is?
真是瞧不起人
You can say that again.
是的，確實如此
Next time, we're going to fight for real.
下次我要讓他拿出真本事
Enter.
進來吧
What do you want?
什麼事？
Dadd——
爸…
Director General Shinomiya.
四之宮長官
I've come to request that Kafka Hibino not be eliminated.
我想請您撤回對日比野卡夫卡的處分
He's saved my life.
他拯救了我的性命
Please consider a light——
拜託您酌情…
Fool.
愚蠢的東西
Did you come to talk about your failures?
你只是來跟我講這種無聊的失敗經驗嗎？
But...
但是…
Look at this.
你看這個
All right.
我看看
His chest X-rays.
這是他的胸部X光片
Look at what's on the left side.
他左胸的東西
He's made it look like a heart,
雖然非常像心臟
but it's a core.
但那是核心
No...
怎麼會？
He's no human.
那傢伙不是人類
He's a Kaiju.
而是怪獸
A Kaiju, like the one that killed your mother.
跟殺死你母親的一樣是怪獸
If you understand now, then leave.
如果聽懂了，就給我出去
Daddy...
爸爸
I still want to believe in him.
即使如此，我還是想要相信他
Another physical exam?
又要進行身體檢查嗎？
How many of these do I have to do?
這要持續到什麼時候啊？
I'd like to sleep in a comfy futon soon...
我差不多想躺下來睡一覺了
I have faith that you'll come back, okay?
我相信你會回來的
There's so much I need to tell everyone.
我還有好多事情必須告訴大家
I can't give up.
我不能放棄
I need to get back there.
我要再次回去那裡
We're being transferred to other divisions?!
調轉到其他部隊？
Temporarily, but yes.
這是暫時的處置
After the last Kaiju attack,
這次的怪獸災害
Tachikawa is down 75% of its functionality as a base.
讓立川基地去失了75%的機能
It's no longer deemed suitable as a place to train new recruits.
因此被判定不適合再作為新人培訓機關
We've seen multiple Daikaiju, first No. 9, then No. 10,
繼9號之後，再加上這次的10號 接連出現大怪獸
and the brass is concerned.
讓高層對此情況心存疑慮
They feel that this may be a chain of connected incidents.
他們擔心這可能是一系列的群發型大災害
So there's more coming?
所以這情況還會繼續嗎？
Not just more, but possibly more at the same time.
不僅如此，也可能會同時發生在多個地方
We must be ready,
我們必須做好準備
and you're the key.
而關鍵就在於你們
We'll be taking the most talented rookies from all the divisions
我們要集結所有部隊裡最優秀的新人
and training them across division boundaries.
不分部隊進行培訓
And that's us?
所以才找上我們？
She said we're talented.
她說我們優秀耶
Is this because of No. 8?
是因為8號的關係嗎？
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
Their real goal is to split up everyone
高層是不是打算 把跟日比野卡夫卡很熟的隊員
who was close to Kafka Hibino and monitor them.
拆散開來，然後加以監視？
Captain Ashiro, if that's the case, I won't obey that order——
亞白隊長，要是這樣我不願聽命…
Wait.
等等
It's noble that you care for your fellow officer,
你們重視同儕的心意實屬難得
but this plan's been under consideration for some time.
但這是以前就研議過的計畫
Kafka Hibino has nothing to do with it.
和日比野卡夫卡無關
I understand.
我瞭解狀況了
But I don't know about just going to another division...
但要轉調到其他部隊，這太突然了
That's right.
是啊
I admired the Third Division, and you, and that's why...
我是因為憧憬第3部隊和你才來的…
I'll do it.
我願意
Do you understand? We're getting split up!
你有搞清楚狀況嗎？我們會被拆散耶
Put some more thought into your answer!
你想清楚再回答吧
I'll do it.
我願意
FATHER
（父親）
Yes, that's right.
是的，沒錯
It's an internal Defense Force matter, so I can't go into details...
這是防衛隊內部的事情 所以無法說得太詳細
But there's someone I want you to save, no matter what.
但我無論如何都想拯救那個人
Yes, I know it's unlikely.
是，我知道可能性很低
Thank you.
拜託您了
Sorry, I didn't feel like I could interrupt.
抱歉，我找不到好時機跟你打招呼
I was the one who walked up here.
是我自己上來這裡的
Don't worry about it.
你別在意
Aoi...
葵
I was talking with my old commander in the JGSDF.
我打電話給以前自衛隊的上司
I wanted him to introduce me to anyone important who could help Kafka.
請他幫忙聯絡有力人士 看看能否干預卡夫卡的處分
That surprises me.
真是意外
I didn't think you were the type to ask for personal favors.
你竟然會因為私情找人關說
Kafka Hibino is a member of the Third Division, like the rest of us.
日比野卡夫卡是我們第3部隊的夥伴
Am I wrong?
不是嗎？
I...
我…
If we can prove you're human, we might be able to save you.
如果可以證明你是人類 也許就能讓你免於遭受處分
Mina's right.
米娜說得沒錯
I'll prove I'm human and go back to everyone.
我要證明自己是人類，回到大家身邊
First I have to get them to hear me out.
首先我得讓他們聽我解釋
I didn't expect the director general to go in himself.
真沒想到長官會親自出馬
That man always settles important matters personally.
越是重要的事情，就越不想假手他人 他這個人就是這樣
Director!
長官！
I'm not a Kaiju!
我不是怪獸！
Release the bindings.
解除他的束縛
It's too dangerous!
這樣太危險了
Who do you think you're talking to?
你是在對誰說話？
If he's really Daikaiju class, he could break them with a wave of his hand.
如果他真的是大怪獸等級 想破壞這種東西是輕而易舉
He's sitting there because he wants to.
他之所以乖乖坐著，全是出於自己的意志
Maybe he'll listen to me!
他也許會聽我解釋
Director General Shinomiya!
四之宮長官
I'm human...
我是人類…
Kafka Hibino!
日比野卡夫卡！
What was that for?
為何要突然攻擊我？
Let me tell you something.
讓我告訴你一件事
In this world, a creature that can stop bullets with its bare skin...
在這個世界上，能以肉身擋住子彈的生物
could never be considered human,
無法稱為人類
Kaiju No. 8.
怪獸8號
Daddy...
爸爸
I'm Kafka Hibino.
我是日比野卡夫卡
You are, huh?
是嗎？
That's the signal. Unlocking FS-1002.
-是暗號 -FS-1002解除鎖定
Request for authorization cleared.
使用許可申請已獲核准
What's that?
那是什麼？
Nerve link cleared.
神經連結完成
Driver and Kaiju No. 2's cell synchronization, all clear.
驅動者與怪獸2號的細胞同步全面完成
FS-1002 activation complete.
FS-1002啟動完畢
Then you can die in that form.
那你就以現在那身姿態受死吧
Commencing disposal of Kaiju No. 8!
開始處理怪獸8號
I won't fully transform!
我不會完全變身
I'll prove I'm human!
我一定要證明我是人類
Oh, crap!
糟了
Kafka!
卡夫卡！
He's still got it.
真是寶刀未老啊
The man they once called the strongest soldier the Defense Force had ever seen.
這個曾被譽為防衛隊史上最強的男人
You look a lot more like a Kaiju now.
你越來越有怪獸的樣子了啊
It'll be bad news if I take a hit from that...
要是被擊中就不妙了
I'll just have to keep dodging until his suit overheats!
我只能努力閃躲，撐到他超出驅動極限了
Why is my body reacting like this?
這個身體反應是怎麼回事？
It's the same as when I fought the Daikaiju!
跟大怪獸對戰時的感覺一樣
But there aren't any...
但這裡並沒有…
Don't tell me...
不會吧
It's reacting to him like he's a Daikaiju?
大怪獸的氣息是從他身上散發出來的？
Kaiju No. 2.
怪獸2號
In 1972, it nearly destroyed Sapporo.
1972年，差點完全摧毀了札幌市
The second Kaiju to ever be given a number.
是第二隻被賦予識別編號的個體
A Daikaiju with incredible destructive power
牠擁有驚人的破壞力
and the pride to never give up until the moment it died...
是一隻很有骨氣，至死不屈的大怪獸
That suit and those arms were made from No. 2.
以這隻怪獸2號所製造的戰鬥服及機械臂
And your father, Isao Shinomiya, is the only one to ever be able to use them.
世上唯一能駕馭的人 就是你父親，四之宮功
So this is what Kikoru was talking about...
原來這就是琪歌露所說的…
Identified Kaiju Weapons:
識別怪獸兵器
the Numbers!
編號武器！
No... don't let that thing hit you again!
不行，我不能再承受攻擊了
Dodge!
我得躲開
I can't move! Why?
我動不了，為什麼？
When...?!
不知不覺間…
Damn it.
可惡
Kafka Hibino!
日比野卡夫卡！
Whew...
太好了
You've finally shown who you really are, Kaiju.
你總算露臉了，怪獸
What? Something's wrong...
什麼？他這個樣子…
Yeah... Something's not right...
果然沒錯，有點不太對勁
What is this?
這是怎麼回事？
I can't control my body!
我控制不了自己的身體
Damn it...
可惡
Forget proving I'm human, I'm totally acting like a Kaiju now!
別說要證明自己是人類了 我這樣根本就是隻怪獸啊
Kill. Kill.
殺死…
Kaiju... Kill...
怪獸，殺死…
Kill...
殺死
No! You're human, right?
住手！你是人類吧？
Kafka Hibino!
日比野卡夫卡！